It was an age of war.
Relying only on his own skill,
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
COMMANDER SOUN HOJO
VOLUME 1
This man
is not a wandering samurai of today.
Hey.
-Do you know who Soun Hojo is?
-No.
He was the first daimyo.
Oh, really?
A masterless samurai,
who no one knew where he came from,
rose up to become the daimyo.
Do you understand how amazing that is?
Right now, my mind is immersed
in the Warring States period.
What?
I have my choir meeting today.
See you later.
"Continued in Volume 2."
Volume 2, Volume 2.
I have to get Volume 2
as soon as possible.
Let's go!
After retiring,
he lost his title as a corporate employee
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story is about
a normal 60-year-old man
who is helped by a masterless samurai,
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
I came to this
used-bookstore alley a lot
when I was a student.
YAGUCHI BOOKSTORE
A TRUE CAFÉ LUNCH
I wonder if that bookstore is still there.
It's here!
It has a new door.
Yes, yes. This smell.
The owner isn't the same as back then.
I read this a long time ago.
This is so nostalgic.
Here it is.
Maybe I'll go to a café and read.
This isn't the type of café I want.
I want a place where the door opens,
and the inside is dim with
a relaxed atmosphere,
and classical music is playing.
The coffee cups and sugar pot
are handpicked by the owner.
I'm looking for a Shōwa era café.
Maybe they don't exist anymore.
There's no way they still exist.
I found one.
Yes, yes, this kind of feel.
KNIT COFFEE
AROMATIC COFFEE
This exterior.
A purist café.
This is what I was looking for.
Yes, yes.
This atmosphere. Just as I imagined.
It's like I've gone back a few decades.
Welcome.
Vienna coffee, please.
Yes.
There's no better place for reading books.
COMMANDER SOUN HOJO
VOL. 2
The excitement of a new first page...
never changes, no matter how old I get.
Thank you for waiting. Vienna coffee.
Thank you.
Enjoy your drink.
It's sweet.
Reminds me of when I was a student
and had a lot of time.
This is just like how it was
40 years ago...
although I've gotten old.
Welcome.
Excuse me.
Dry curry, please.
-I'll have the pilaf.
-And for your drinks?
Iced coffee.
-The same.
-Yes.
Noon already.
I can't read if I'm hungry.
BEEF CURRY
DELUXE CURRY
SPAGHETTI (TOMATO OR MEAT)
Neapolitan!
My mouth is filled
with the taste of ketchup.
Excuse me.
Thank you for waiting. Neapolitan.
This is a classic café Neapolitan.
Bon appétit.
Delicious!
It's delicious, but...
Excuse me?
Do you any parmesan?
-Yes. I'll bring it now.
-And...
-Tabasco, too, please.
-Yes.
Thank you for waiting.
Lots of parmesan cheese...
and a little Tabasco.
Yes, yes!
This is it!
Wait, I could do more with this.
That's good!
Delicious!
Thank you for the meal.
That was delicious.
Thanks for waiting.
-That's why you're so stupid.
-Shut up.
You threw away 30,000 yen
on that big bet.
No, that was an investment.
-You'll never get it back.
-I'm confident about the ninth race.
Oh, let's hear your prediction, master.
They're so loud.
I think he'll win.
-My bet's on him.
-Do you think he'll win?
-You won the bet, didn't you?
-Excuse me.
-Iced coffee.
-Two.
-Yes.
-And which is your big bet?
Big bet? On the ninth race,
my money is all on Lightning Sunday!
You... Are you trying
to throw away money again?
I'm not throwing anything away!
-Who is the opponent?
-Pure White.
He always finishes 14th.
Because it was a dirt course!
Do I have to tell them to be quiet?
"Excuse me. Could you be quiet, please?"
I have to be more firm
with people like this.
"Hey, shut up!"
No. If I say that, it'd start a fight.
What would a samurai do
in a situation like this?
You're so loud.
Hey. Are you talking to us?
Who else is there?
You're not from around here.
Hey. Listen.
Around here, no one messes with us.
Small dogs tend to bark a lot.
What did you say?
Want to fight?
Bastard!
I'm fed up with this.
I don't think you're going to win.
Why do we even bet on horse races?
I want to know, too.
All right, I'm going.
I'm going to say something.
One fruit parfait, please.
Yes.
And...
may I change seats?
Go ahead.
I feel so ashamed.
You're bothering the other customers.
Could you please keep it down?
-Sorry.
Here's your coffee.
A samurai.
"You're so loud."
"Small dogs tend to bark a lot."
I couldn't say it.
Hello.
What time will you be home?
I'll be back in about an hour.
We're having sukiyaki today.
Sukiyaki?
Nishikawa sent us some Yonezawa beef.
Oh, really?
I see.
Yes.
All right.
I better walk to the station
to make myself hungry!
Subtitle translation by
Hoday Stearns